<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
  xmlns:admin="http://webns.net/mvcb/"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">

  <channel>
    <title>Changeset based Build Numbering</title>
    <link>http://www.woodwardweb.com/vsts/changeset_based.html</link>
    <description><![CDATA[Here at Teamprise we've recently changed our build numbering scheme.&nbsp; We use the traditional Major.Minor.Revision.Build approach with Major.Minor.Revision being the only thing an end user should care about and Major.Minor the only thing we would every do any marketing for.&nbsp;...]]></description>
    <dc:language>en-us</dc:language>
    <dc:creator>Martin</dc:creator>
    <dc:date>2007-02-13T14:10:52+00:00</dc:date>
    <admin:generatorAgent rdf:resource="http://www.movabletype.org/?v=4.32-en" />
    <admin:errorReportsTo rdf:resource="mailto:webmaster@woodwardweb.com"/>

    
    <item>
    <title>Comment by GregM+00:00</title>
    <link>http://www.woodwardweb.com/vsts/changeset_based.html#c000955</link>
    <description>We do the incrementing value as well, in a header file that gets modified and checked in as the first part of the build step (we&apos;re a C++ shop).  My question is how do you get the build number into the product?
</description>
    <dc:date>2007-02-13T23:35:31+00:00</dc:date>  <comments>http://www.woodwardweb.com/mt/mt-comments.cgi?entry_id=737</comments>   
    <dc:creator>GregM</dc:creator>
  </item>
  
    <item>
    <title>Comment by Martin Woodward+00:00</title>
    <link>http://www.woodwardweb.com/vsts/changeset_based.html#c000956</link>
    <description>Greg,

In the java world it is really easy.  We get the changeset data into a variable in Ant and then we use that variable to do a number of substitutions in .properties files but also to name the jar files.  Eclipse uses a naming convention to indicate which is the latest version (which works very similar to the 0.0.0.qualifier system used by .NET Assemblies.

So, to answer your question when we do the check-out of the files we then do a string substitution inside those file replacing it with the build number that we have generated.

Not sure if that helps in your C++ world.  I&apos;m afriad I get scared now-a-days when I have to work in unmanaged code...</description>
    <dc:date>2007-02-14T16:05:07+00:00</dc:date>  <comments>http://www.woodwardweb.com/mt/mt-comments.cgi?entry_id=737</comments>   
    <dc:creator>Martin Woodward</dc:creator>
  </item>
  
    <item>
    <title>Comment by GregM+00:00</title>
    <link>http://www.woodwardweb.com/vsts/changeset_based.html#c000959</link>
    <description>Okay, so you do change the source after it is retrieved from source control.  That&apos;s the main think I was wondering about.  I suppose we could also hook it up using an environment variable.  We already use an environment variable to control whether or not the build is an &quot;official&quot; one.  

I wonder if the Vault command line client would return this value for us.  I don&apos;t see anything obvious in the help.  I&apos;ll have to do some digging.

This would result in a huge inflation of our build numbers... we hit a transaction number of 100000 back in December (we have history in our tree for over 10 years, it was imported from VSS).  I&apos;m guessing that would really confuse some people.  Thanks for the idea.
</description>
    <dc:date>2007-02-15T23:43:42+00:00</dc:date>  <comments>http://www.woodwardweb.com/mt/mt-comments.cgi?entry_id=737</comments>   
    <dc:creator>GregM</dc:creator>
  </item>
  
    <item>
    <title>Comment by GregM+00:00</title>
    <link>http://www.woodwardweb.com/vsts/changeset_based.html#c000960</link>
    <description>Oops, &quot;the main thing&quot;, not &quot;the main think&quot;.
</description>
    <dc:date>2007-02-15T23:52:09+00:00</dc:date>  <comments>http://www.woodwardweb.com/mt/mt-comments.cgi?entry_id=737</comments>   
    <dc:creator>GregM</dc:creator>
  </item>
  
    <item>
    <title>Comment by Martin Woodward+00:00</title>
    <link>http://www.woodwardweb.com/vsts/changeset_based.html#c000961</link>
    <description>Greg,

I&apos;d have to ask my colleagues over on the SourceGear side of the fence about the usage of the Vault command line as it is something I don&apos;t do every day.

I would think that possibly something like &quot;vault HISTORY -rowlimit 1 pathToProject&quot; might give you enough to be able to parse out the changeset - however I&apos;d have to ask them.

Good luck,

Martin.</description>
    <dc:date>2007-02-16T11:56:44+00:00</dc:date>  <comments>http://www.woodwardweb.com/mt/mt-comments.cgi?entry_id=737</comments>   
    <dc:creator>Martin Woodward</dc:creator>
  </item>
  
    <item>
    <title>Comment by Joshua Flanagan+00:00</title>
    <link>http://www.woodwardweb.com/vsts/changeset_based.html#c000994</link>
    <description>I was using this same approach for my projects at work, until we ran into the UInt16 limit of .NET version numbers (which didn&apos;t take long at all, since the changeset is global to the entire server, and we have hundreds of project teams using the same server).
Now we have to do some ugly modulo math and split the changeset number between the Revision and Build.</description>
    <dc:date>2007-03-26T01:37:54+00:00</dc:date>  <comments>http://www.woodwardweb.com/mt/mt-comments.cgi?entry_id=737</comments>   
    <dc:creator>Joshua Flanagan</dc:creator>
  </item>
  
    <item>
    <title>Comment by Vladiv+00:00</title>
    <link>http://www.woodwardweb.com/vsts/changeset_based.html#c001275</link>
    <description>Hi Martin,

You mentioned: &quot;I&apos;m also going to be modifying the CruiseControl.NET integration to TFS to make versioning based on changeset numbers easier.&quot; Do you still have plans to do so?

Thanks, Vladiv</description>
    <dc:date>2009-01-20T19:34:56+00:00</dc:date>  <comments>http://www.woodwardweb.com/mt/mt-comments.cgi?entry_id=737</comments>   
    <dc:creator>Vladiv</dc:creator>
  </item>
  
  </channel>
</rss>